houseofnames.com 2007-10-14

# Privacy Statement - Knowledge Base, HouseofNames.com

Text Size  **Houseofnames** > **Knowledge Base** > Privacy Statement 

## Privacy Statement

Last Updated on 2007/04/17 

Table of Contents

  * Online Ordering Help
  * Newsletter Opt-out
  * Complaint Procedure

| 

  * Truste Certification
  * American Customers
  * Privacy Policy Details

---|---  

## Truste Certification

[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.houseofnames.com&sealid=101) Houseofnames.com, an Internet property of Swyrich Corporation, has created this statement in order to demonstrate our strong commitment to protecting your privacy. This statement discloses how we collect and disseminate information. 

Swyrich Corporation is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.houseofnames.com. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users' privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If users have policy questions or concerns, you can contact the Policy Administrator. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or it is not satisfactorily addressed, you can then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process [(http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php)](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Houseofnames.com web site to resolve users concerns. 

## Online Ordering Help

Phone and E-Mail messages can be left with us 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. 

### Mon-Fri:

For immediate help with questions you have while ordering online, please call our Customer Service Representative (9:30AM-4PM, EST). 

### Sat-Sun:

For the weekend interval, please allow up to two business days for a reply to inquiries by E-Mail or Phone. 

### Holidays:

During holidays, or holiday periods, please allow a delay (3-10 days, depending on circumstances) for a response to inquiries by E-Mail or Phone. 

### Postal Mail:

For a formal response to requests made via postal mail, please allow up to 30 days for a mail response. 

### FAQs:

For FAQs and Tracking My Order/Profile Updates, see our customer service information page. 

## American Customers

For U.S. Customers with immediate order form questions, see Online Ordering Help. 

This section does not apply to products downloaded over the Internet.

### Ultimate Consignee ID:

As of Mar. 2007, U.S. Customs defines an imported number as "either your IRS business registration number, or if your business is not registered with the IRS or you do not have a business, your social security number." This number is also referred to as the Ultimate Consignee ID number, and for businesses as a Tax Id or EIN. 

### Consignee ID on Order Forms:

When you make an order requiring importation to the United States, the value of which exceeds $200 USD, our order form requests that you provide an importer number. This ID is in addition to your regular shipping information, and ensures a speedy clearance of your order through U.S. Customs. For orders under $200 USD, the US Address of the consignee is sufficient for importation of goods. 

### Consignee ID Usage:

The consignee number is provided only for shipping purposes, to U.S. Customs in electronic form and printed on a hard copy of the invoice shipped with the product. U.S Customs, and shipping companies, will have access to the ID. 

### References

For further background on U.S. Customs requirements, visit the following external links (as of Mar, 2007): 

## Privacy Policy Details

Contents

  * Information Collection
  * Information Usage
  * Information Usage 3rd Party
  * Information Retention

| 

  * Information Control
  * Information Access
  * Information Security
  * Protection for Children

| 

  * E-Mail Communications
  * Cookies
  * Testimonials
  * External Links

| 

  * Trade Marks
  * Change Control
  * Enforcement Procedure
  * Privacy Contact (Admin)

---|---|---|---  

## Information Collection

### Visiting the Site:

We do not collect any personal information about you, when you visit the Houseofnames.com web site, unless you use our contact-us, order, or affiliate program forms. 

Our on-site web server system tracks standard web browser data, such as IP address, browser type, referring web site address, domain name, access times, and pages accessed on the site. This collected log data helps diagnose problems with our web servers, monitor certain aspects of web queries, analyze trends, and administer our Web site. Note that IP Addresses may be considered personal information by some, due to the possibility of tracing a vistor via Internet Service Providers. All collected web server log data, including the IP address, are not linked to any personal information that you may provide when contacting us, or ordering from us. 

### Contacting via E-Mail:

To contact us via E-Mail, we require as a minimum your name and E-Mail address so that we may contact you. Additional information may be given so as to describe your request or concern. 

Note, E-Mail is an unsecured form of communication. Please take due care as to what you write into an E-Mail, in particular do not include credit card or other confidential data. 

### Placing an Order:

If you place an order through our secure on-line form, or over the phone, we request the following personal information: 

  * Name
  * Telephone Number (optional on E-mail orders)
  * Billing Address
  * Shipping Address (if different from billing address)
  * Payment Information
  * E-Mail Address (optional on phone orders)
  * Password of your making, to allow you to track orders on-line (optional)
  * Consignee Identifier (conditional requirement; refer to American Customers section) 
  * Recipient E-Mail Address (when ordering a Gift Card)
  * Gift Card ID and Password (when using a Gift Card)
  * and whether to opt-out from future Houseofnames.com E-Mail newsletters

### Joining the Affiliate Program:

If you sign-up to our Affiliate Program, we require your 

  * Name
  * E-Mail Address
  * Preferred Payment Method
  * Address
  * Phone Number
  * Password (of your own making)
  * Web Site Address
  * Description of your web site/Business

For more information on the Affiliate Program, refer to affiliate home page. 

### Using the Surname Search Feature:

If you use the "Search For Surname" tool, and you find your name is not present on the search results page, you can opt-in to send Houseofnames.com a notification that your name is not present in our list of display names. This notification requires your E-Mail Address, and includes your Surname, so that we may contact you should the requested surname become available at a later date. 

### Receiving Newsletters:

When you receive newsletters or promotional E-Mail from Swyrich Corporation, we may use a simple web beacon to determine whether the E-Mail has been opened. This beacon is not used to validate personal information. 

### Demographics:

Houseofnames.com does not collect any demographic information. 

### Third Party Data Linkage:

Houseofnames.com does not link your personal information to any third party data that we may obtain. 

In the case of IP Addresses, a third party tool may be used to customize your web experience based on an IP's geographic location, but no data is given to the third party. 

## Third Party Personally Identifiable Information

### Email A Friend:

To use our "Email To A Friend" referral form, we require your E-Mail address and your friend's E-Mail addresses in order to send the message. Additional, optional, data may be provided in the form by you. We will automatically send your friend a one-time E-Mail inviting them to visit our web site. 

These E-Mail addresses, and the E-Mail content, are not collected, stored, tracked, or linked to any other data collected by Kingpins.net. Comments made in the E-Mail message are not censored in anyway, and are deemed confidential to both parties. We are not responsible for any personal identifiable information you choose to send within this E-Mail. 

### Gift Card Program:

When a customer purchases a Gift Card for another person, the form requests the E-Mail Address of the recipient. A one-time Gift Card E-Mail notification is sent to the recipient upon completion of the purchase. Optional data can be included in the notification: recipient and sender names, and a message. 

Note, E-Mail addresses, names, and comments that may be included in these type of E-Mails are not collected by us, nor censored in anyway, and are deemed confidential to both parties. Keep in mind that E-Mail is unsecured communication. E-Mail data is not linked to the senders personal information. 

## Information Usage

Your personal information is used to deliver in-house services, improve our sites and products, or to carry out the transactions you have requested. We also use your personal information to communicate with you. 

### When Ordering:

Personal data provided when ordering on our site are used as follows: 

  * Clarify details of orders
  * Send order confirmations
  * Reply to your questions
  * Deliver purchased product to you
  * Charge you the cost of goods
  * View shipping data

Note, to view your order's shipping progress, a secure limited-entry area of the site is provided. The login service provides you external links to courier web sites. 

### E-Mail:

  * Refer to the E-Mail Communications section. 

### Testimonials:

  * Refer to the Testimonials section. 

### Third Party Intermediary Services:

  * Agents:  
We use outside couriers to ship orders. We use either credit card processing companies or Paypal to facilitate payment processing of your order. 

Please be aware that the privacy policy of couriers, credit card companies, or Paypal, governs the use and collection of information. In the case of Paypal, some of your personal identifiable information you provide to them for payment transaction purposes is shared with us via the Paypal secure web site. 

  * Service Providers:  
We do not use third parties to provide services on our site. Web server logs are captured on on-site servers belonging to Swyrich Corporation, only. 

### Judicial Requirements:

  * We reserve the right to disclose personal identifiable information as required by law, and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our site. 

## E-Mail Communications

We may send you electronic communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, newsletters, service issue notices, and security announcements. We currently do not send out customer survey letters. We do not request customers to update personal information via E-Mail or on-line forms. 

### Customer Newsletters:

If you subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your Name and E-Mail address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. 

To stop receiving Houseofnames.com Newsletters, use the opt-out link provided in the E-Mail, or send a request to our Customer Service Representative with the subject "Newsletter Opt-out". 

### Customer Service-related Announcements:

We will send customers service-related announcements, when it is necessary to do so. For instance, we will send you a confirmation E-Mail when you place an order, send a recipient notification of a Gift Card purchased by another, send one or more recipients notification via the "E-Mail a Friend" tool, send you order processing related E-Mails, and, if necessary, send you an E-Mail notification should our service be temporarily suspended. 

Customers can opt-out of these service-related E-Mail communications, except for both the Gift Card and E-Mail a Friend notifications. These announcements are not promotional in nature, and it is recommended that you receive them as they provide information about an order or service. If you do not wish to receive such communications, excluding the above exceptions, please contact our Customer Service Representative with the subject "Service Announcements Opt-out". 

### Affiliate Service-related Announcements:

We will send members of our Affiliate Program E-Mail communications related to the service. There is no opt-out for such communications. 

## Information Retention

### Personal Information:

Personal information is retained in a secure database. The customer's personal information provided when ordering is retained indefinitely except for credit card details. Credit card data are retained for 90 days, only. 

### Cookies:

Houseofnames.com web site cookies that are placed on the customer's machine are retained for 100 days. For further information on cookie usage, see section Cookies. 

### Web Server Logs:

Web site logs are retained for a minimum of 45 days. 

## Information Control

We will not sell, give, share, or trade your personal information with any company that is not part of Swyrich Corporation, except as disclosed in this statement. Within the Swyrich Corporation, information is used for the limited purposes stated here-in. Personal information will only be used for the stated purposes. We also do not allow other companies to offer our customer's products or services, unless you opt-in to receive such notifications. 

If you wish to opt-out of Houseofnames.com E-Mail notifications, refer to E-Mail Opt-out Procedure. 

## Information Access

Access to personal information is limited or restricted, depending on the data type. To access personal data, customers must be able to identify they are the owner. For access/update requests, please allow time for a response (see Online Ordering Help.). If you need to update your profile information, please refer to the [Sign-in](https://secure.swyrich.com/customerlogin.asp?sId=&Licensee=54323) page. 

### Accessing Order Status:

The status (order/contents/shipping information) of a customer's order may be checked by an on-line login account created upon their first order. If necessary, fax or phone can also be used to retrieve status information. 

### Accessing Affiliate Statistics:

An affilate may access statistics by an on-line login account created when they joined the program. 

### Updating Personal Information:

Personal information stored by Swyrich Corporation may be updated by calling a Customer Service Representative. (Please do not use E-Mail to communicate critical personal data, such as a credit card number.) Information can be either updated, modified, or deleted. 

### Accessing Personal Information:

To get a written copy of your personal information we may have on hand, to challenge the accuracy and completeness of said information, please make a request in writing to our Privacy Administrator. 

### Employee Acccess:

Employees of Swyrich Corporation do not have access to your personal information, except as follows: Customer Service Representatives, for order processing and shipping, and Database Administration via secure access. 

### Restrictions:

Review sections Information Control and Information Usage for other possible restrictions or limitations. 

## Information Security

We are committed to protecting the security of your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. We use security technology and procedures to protect information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We store information on a global secure server, with limited access, that is located in controlled facilities. 

When critical personal information is transmitted, such as during the order process, we protect it through the use of 128 bit SSL encryption. The shopping page SSL Certificate expires April 18, 2009. 

### Passwords:

If you have created a login account, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone, log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. On third party computers, you may wish to take additional precautions by deleting any data you may have created on said machine, including deleting your passwords that may have been collected by the browser - you can delete passwords remembered by a browser using the browser's preferences tool. 

### Audits:

Houseofnames.com Internet web server security is audited daily by way of a third party [security service](http://www.scanalert.com/RatingVerify?ref=www.houseofnames.com). Our [security policy](http://www.houseofnames.com/xq/asp/sId./kbId.181/title.Security+Certificates/qx/knowledgebase.htm) and procedures are reviewed periodically, and employees are made aware of security policies and procedures. 

## Information Protection for Children

Houseofnames.com is a general audience site, and is not directed at children. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. 

## Cookies

We place one or more cookies on your computer. Cookies do not contain personal information. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. No third party cookie is placed on your computer. 

Our cookies aid you when shopping on the House of Names site, when returning to an uncompleted shopping activity, when returning to the site after a first purchase, and when visiting the site via an E-Mail Newsletter. An additional cookie may be created when shopping via a House of Names Affiliate. We do link information we store in some cookies to some personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

The Newsletter cookie is used for tracking whether an E-Mail is opened once. A simple web beacon is used in the Newsletter in order to support this, to unobtrusively contact our servers when the Newsletter is opened. 

If you disable cookies in your web browser, you can still view content on the web site, and place orders at the time of the visit. 

Cookies are retained on your computer for a limited time period (see the Information Retention section). 

Note, when you use a third party computer to visit the houseofnames.com site, keep in mind that cookies will be created on that machine. You may wish to take personal security precautions by deleting data you place on third party computers; you can delete cookies using the browser's preferences tool. 

## Testimonials

If you submit a testimonial for use on this site, you should be aware that any personal identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of the Houseofnames.com pages and or forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. 

We are not responsible for the personal identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. Submission of a testimonial implies consent for posting the testimonial. Our current practice is to change the submitters full name, if provided, into initials before posting the testimonial on the web site. 

## External Links

The Houseofnames.com site contains a few links to external web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are moving to another web site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours. 

## Trade Marks

Any trademark referenced on this site is the property of the trademark owner. 

## Change Control

Should we change our policy, we will notify you of the change in this online privacy statement. We will keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you herein, and, optionally, on other House of Names web site pages we deem appropriate (such as the home page). 

## Enforcement Procedure

If you have questions regarding this privacy policy, first contact our Privacy Administrator. An acknowledgment reply is normally sent immediately, but please allow at least two business days for a response to your specific inquiry. 

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, not later then 30 days after it was made, contact one of the following external web site organizations: 

  * TRUSTe
  * [BBB _Online_](http://www.bbbonline.org/consumer/complaint.asp) (File a Compliant page)
  * [Privacy Commission of Canada](http://www.privcom.gc.ca/) (Re: PIPEDA & Privacy Act, refer to their Contact Us page)

Swyrich Corporation enforces this online privacy statement within the coporation. 

## Privacy Contact (Administrative)

Houseofnames.com welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement and its practices. 

For immediate help with online ordering, see Online Ordering Help. 

For general questions regarding privacy issues, contact us by one of the following means. Please allow at least two business days for a reply to inquiries by E-Mail or Phone. 

  * `Toll Free..: 888-468-7686 x226`
  * `Phone......: 613-384-9986 x226`
  * `Fax........: 613-384-0606 `
  * `Email......:[ MailTo](mailto:privacy@swyrich.com?Subject=HON%20Privacy%20Adminstration) (Note: E-Mail is non-confidential communication)`
  * `Postal Mail:`   
Privacy Administrator   
House Of Names   
Swyrich Corporation   
830 Development Drive   
Kingston, ON, Canada   
K7M 5V7 

### Tools

E-Newsletters:
